MORARU **ECATERINA**

PRODUCT DESIGNER

I design large-scale digital products and platforms, enjoying solutions that empower the target user. Having a technical background, I thrive collaborating with engineering teams while focusing on end-user usability. I have experience involving open source communities in the development process.

EXPERIENCE

Oct 2021 - Present

Senior UX Designer / Analog Devices

Upgrading Analog's evaluation tools' experience on the vLab platform, together with 9 other UX designers.

Sep 2019 — Sep 2021

Lead Product Designer / Arezzo Sky

Designing from scratch the next-gen no-code mobile platform for data processing, together with a team of 25 engineers and another designer.

Nov 2015 — Aug 2019

Lead Interaction Designer / XWiki

Orchestrated the user experience across all XWiki's products. Designed tools and services that bridged the open-source community with the professional enterprise target.

Jan 2014 — Oct 2015

Applications Team Manager / XWiki

Managed a team of 5 developers in assuring a consistent user experience across 20 most valuable applications selected from over 600 open source community extensions.

Apr 2013 — Dec 2013

Front-end Team Lead / XWiki

Proposed and integrated the most longevive and extensible skin system for XWiki: the Flamingo Skin.

Mar 2009 — Mar 2013

Interaction Designer / XWiki

Designed the Extension Manager, App Within Minutes, Search, Activity Stream features for XWiki, an open-source scalable platform for developing collaborative applications. valicac@gmail.com +40 (742) 543-821

Iași, Romania www.risherry.ro

EXPERTISE

user-experience / user-research interaction-design / ux-engineer prototyping / usability-testing conceptualization / design-system design-sprint / design-patterns consistency / accessibility standards-compliance / front-end roadmap-planning / open-source

COMMUNITIES

Feb 2015 — Present

Co-organizer

OpenSourceDesign.net Growing an international community with over 3000 members that evanghelizes more open design processes in software development.

May 2008 — Nov 2019

Mentor

Google Summer of Code Introducing hundreds of students from all over the world to open source software development.

Oct 2007 — Mar 2011

Collaborator Teaching Assistant

Faculty of Computer Science, A. I. Cuza University, Iaşi Pioneered teaching classes of "Human-Computer Interaction" to computer-science students.

EDUCATION

2007 - 2009

M. Sc. Software Engineering

Faculty of Computer Science. A. I. Cuza University, Iaşi

2003 - 2007

B. Sc. Computer Science

Faculty of Computer Science, A. I. Cuza University, Iași







